A Guide to the J.J. Lankes Woodcuts owned by Louis I. Jaffé, 1920-1940
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
J.J. Lankes Woodcuts owned by Louis I. Jaffé 1920-1940
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9924-a
45 wood engravings.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Louis I. Jaffé, 1974 June 14.
Scope and Content
Many of Lankes' woodcuts are inscribed to Louis I. Jaffé. Among them are scenes in Buffalo, N.Y., Rochester, N.Y., Georgetown (Washington, D.C.), Hilton Village, Va., Norfolk, Va., Rothenburg, Germany, Troutdale, Va., Williamsburg, Va., and the Old Cape Henry Lighthouse.
Contents List
- "The Temptation," no. 15, by J.J. Lankes 1920, Woodcut
- "Hilltop," by J.J. Lankes 1922, Woodcut
- "Cottage in Winter," by J.J. Lankes 192[2], Woodcut
- "Buffalo Harbor," no. 15, by J.J. Lankes 1922, Woodcut
- "Old Gate, Rochester," by J.J. Lankes 1922, Woodcut
- a house and tree with moon above, by J.J. Lankes 1923, Woodcut
- " 'N' Street House, Georgetown, D.C.," by J.J. Lankes 1923, Woodcut
- "May Days, An Anthology of Masses - Liberator Verse," by J.J. Lankes 1924, Woodcut
- "Koholdgasse - Rothenburg," by J.J. Lankes 1926, Woodcut
- "Outpost of Commerce," no. 4, by J.J. Lankes 1927, Woodcut
- "Mike Evan's Place, Buffalo," no. 12, by J.J. Lankes 1927, Woodcut
- a house and tree with moon above, by J.J. Lankes 1928 May 1, Woodcut
- a road with fence and trees in winter, by J.J. Lankes 1929 April 19, Woodcut
- a house with auto out front, by [J.J. Lankes] 1929, Woodcut
- "Williamsburg Cottage," by J.J. Lankes 1929, Woodcut
- "Hired Man's House," by J.J. Lankes 1929, Woodcut
- "Troutdale, Virginia," no. 11, by J.J. Lankes 1930, Woodcut
- "Willoughboy Spit," trial proof, by J.J. Lankes 1930, Woodcut
- "Noon Hour," trial proof, by J.J. Lankes 1931, Woodcut
- "Is this Aht, or is it criticism," by J.J. Lankes 1931, Woodcut
- "Main Street, Troutdale, Virginia," no. 2, by J.J. Lankes 1932, Woodcut
- "Printemps," by J.J. Lankes 1932, Woodcut
- "Printemps," by J.J. Lankes 1932, Woodcut
- "Cornfiel," no. 11, by J.J. Lankes 1933, Woodcut
- "Sunday Afternoon," trial impression, by J.J. Lankes 1934, Woodcut
- "Old Cape Henry Lighthouse," trial impression by J.J. Lankes 1935, Woodcut
- "Old Cape Henry Lighthouse," no. 1, by J.J. Lankes 1935, Woodcut
- "Spring Twilight," no. 29, by J.J. Lankes 1936, Woodcut
- "Spring Twilight," no. 32, by J.J. Lankes 1936, Woodcut
- "Old House, Norfolk, Virginia," no. 4, by J.J. Lankes 1940, Woodcut
- "Garrow's Barnyard," no. 15/50, by J.J. Lankes 1940, Woodcut
- "Starsplitter Dawn," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "Toad," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "Spring Plowing," [no. 12], by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "Coach," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "Little Church," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "Road to Bennington, Vermont," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "Sleighride," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "March Day in George town," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- an old house on a Norfolk street corner, by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "Gray's Elegy, Stanza XXI," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- a barn and horse in winter, by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "Village Church," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut
- "Autumn," by J.J. Lankes n.d., Woodcut